Kinesiology Department. Course and curriculum files. 1919-1978.
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kinesiology Department. Course and curriculum files.
1919-1978
University Archives Record Series 330
UCLA Library Special Collections
2.8 linear ft. (7 boxes)
Record Series 330 contains the course and curriculum files of UCLA's Kinesiology Department, generated between 1919 and 1978.
University of California, Los Angeles. Kinesiology Department.
Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Historical note
The Department of Kinesiology trace its origins to the Department of Physical Education, which was established in 1915 as part of the Los Angeles State Normal School. In 1919 the department became part of the Teachers College of the Southern Branch, with separate departments for men and women. During the 1920s, the department's efforts were devoted to the training of Physical Education teachers and the administration of the Physical Education classes that were required of all undergraduates. In 1932 the Men's and Women's Gymnasiums were completed. In 1938 the M.S. degree in Physical Education was authorized. In 1939 the department became part of the newly established College of Applied Arts. In 1952 separate divisions for men and women were eliminated. In 1960 the College of Applied Arts was dissolved and replaced by the College of Fine Arts. The Physical Education Department was then transferred to the College of Letters and Science, Division of Life Sciences. In 1962 the revised physical education major was approved and focused on Kinesiology (the science of human movement) and one of three allied fields: physiology, psychology, or sociology. In 1973 the department changed its name to Kinesiology. When Donald T. Hardy retired in 1976, he was recognized as the founding father of the Kinesiology department. The department first offered a Ph.D. degree in Kinesiology in 1979. In 1990 the Kinesiology Department changed its name to the Physiological Sciences Department.
Scope and Content
Record Series 330 contains the course and curriculum files of UCLA's Kinesiology Department, generated between 1919 and 1978. Files regard courses in both kinesiology and physical education, curriculum studies, course equivalents at other universities, graduate curriculum, teaching, athletic and fitness tests, and other operational materials.
This is an inactive record series; no additional University records are expected to be added.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 3466859
- Proficiency required for Phys. Ed. majors., 1967. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Activity clinics and proficiency tests., 1965-1968. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Agreements of the faculty on the revised course offerings., 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Announcements - department policies., 1977-1979. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Basic Movement - description and analysis., 1965. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Body of knowledge., 1960. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Conceptual framework of kinesiology., 1963. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Course contributions to each area of kinesiology., 1965. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Course equivalents - Berkeley., 1943-1945. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Course equivalents - quarter courses., 1965-1966. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Course numbers and descriptions., 1966 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Course revisions., 1961-1962. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Curriculum - changes proposed., 1962. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Curriculum - new, initial issue., 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Curriculum studies - Health Education., 1947. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Curriculum studies - Physical Education., 1937-1939; 1947. (Box 1, Folders 16-17)
- Curriculum studies - Physical Therapy., 1951-1954. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Curriculum studies - Recreation Education., 1949. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Curriculum - undergraduate, revised., 1863 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Elementary school program., 1960. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Enrollment in adapted physical education classes., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Evaluation of instruction program., 1975-1977. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Test - General Athletic Ability - instructions., 1943. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Grade allotments., 1940-1941. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Graduate courses projected., 1950-1960. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Graduate degrees - Health Education., 1952. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Graduate study - alumnae input, curriculum., 1970. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Guidebook Revision - M.S. Degree., 1953. (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Injury - reports and forms., 1966-1975. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Instructor's Guidebook - Physical Education for General College., 1954-1955. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Instruction - Report on Effectiveness., 1954-1955. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Junior Colleges - information concerning transfer credit., 1952-1963. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Justification for Health Ed. curriculum in the physical Ed. Department., 1959. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Kinesiology 2B - materials, exam., 1977. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Kinesiology 14 - materials, exams., 1976-1977. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Kinesiology 16 - preparation for midterm., 1976-1977. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Kinesiology 44 - outline of class., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Kinesiology 108 - materials, exams., 1976-1977. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Kinesiology 109 - class schedule., 1977. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Kinesiology 110 - materials, exams., 1976-1977. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Kinesiology 111 - final exam., 1976-1977. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Kinesiology 111 - labs - materials., 1977. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Kinesiology 115 - course outline., 1977. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Kinesiology 117 - class schedule, midterm exam., 1976-1977. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Kinesiology 118 - materials, exams., 1977. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Kinesiology 130 - lab materials, exams., 1977-1978. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Kinesiology 131 - lab material., 1977. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Kinesiology 132 - materials, exams., 1976-1977. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Kinesiology 134A - exams., 1977. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Kinesiology 139 - lab materials, exams., 1976-1977. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Kinesiology 140 - materials, exams., 1976-1977. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Kinesiology 145 - materials, exams., 1976-1977. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Kinesiology 150/151 - materials, exams., 1977. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Kinesiology 160 - course outline, exams., 1977. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Kinesiology 170B - materials., 1976-1977. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Kinesiology 175 - exams., 1976-1977. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Kinesiology 178 - materials, exams., 1977-1978. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Kinesiology 191B - course schedule, bibliography., 1976-1977. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Kinesiology 210A - materials, exams., 1976-1977. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Kinesiology 210B - materials, exams., 1977-1978. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Kinesiology 230A - materials., 1976-1977. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Kinesiology 240 - materials, exams., 1977. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Kinesiology 250 - course outline., 1976-1977. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Kinesiology 255 - materials., 1976-1977. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Kinesiology 256 - materials., 1976-1977. (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Kinesiology 262 - materials., 1977. (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Objectives of general education and of physical education. (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Physical Education - Four Year Curriculum., 1943-1945. (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Physical Education - Master of Science Degree., 1953-1959. (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Physical Education - Master of Science Degree - recipients., 1923-1959. (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Physical Education - philosophy., 1950-1970. (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Physical Education - Teaching Major - information., 1958-1967. (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Physical Education - Teaching Major - prerequisites for allied fields., 1959-1967. (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Physical Education - Teaching Minor - information., 1953-1970. (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Physical Education - required Vs elective units., 1956-1965. (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Physical Education - undergraduate courses., 1962 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Physical Education unit., 1957-1963. (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Physical Education 1 - hearing., 1957 Apr. (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Physical Education 1 - letter to Chancellor Knudsen., 1960 Mar. (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Physical Education 1 - military conditioning., 1961-1962. (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Physical Education 1 - program to cultural recreation., 1967. (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Physical Education 1 - sports clinics., 1965-1966. (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Physical Education 13 - material for physical fitness., 1942-1943. (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Physical Education 26 - Experimental Program Report., 1951. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Physical Education 26 - general class materials., 1952. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Physical Education 26 - evaluations of student teaching., 1953. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Physical Education 26 - teaching by juniors., 1953. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Physical Education 29 - daily record, class minutes - fall semester., 1949. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Physical Education 29 - study of movement., 1949. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Physical Education - study of movement - notes and report., 1949. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Physical Education 29/30 - final report., 1950. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Physical Education 29 - daily record - fall semester., 1950-1951. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Physical Education 29 - class minutes., 1950-1951. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Physical Education 29 - report to core staff - understanding self., 1950-1951. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Physical Education 29 - core evaluations., 1950-1952. (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Physical Education 29 - final report - spring semester., 1953. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Physical Education 30 - notes and exams., 1948-1949. (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Physical Education 30 - class record - spring semester., 1950. (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Physical Education 30 - report to core staff., 1951. (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Physical Education 30 - materials and notes - spring semester., 1951. (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Physical Education 30 - basketball unit - objectives, exams., 1952. (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Physical Education 30 - final report - spring semester., 1952. (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Physical Education 30 - final report - fall semester., 1952. (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Physical Education 30 - final report - fall semester., 1953. (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Physical Education 32 - final report - spring semester., 1954. (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Physical Education 132 - final report - fall semester., 1951-1952. (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Physical Education 132 - public performance unit., 1952-1953. (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Physical Education 132 - individual class evaluation., 1953. (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Physical Education 132 - individual class evaluation conferences (s 2)., 1953. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Physical Education 132 - general materials., 1954-1955. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Physical Education 145 - objectives, lesson plans., 1952-1955. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Physical Education 152 - final report - spring semester., 1952. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Physical Education 152 - general materials., 1952-1953. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Physical Education 152 - general materials., 1953-1955. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Physical Education 154 - exams., nd. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Physical Education 199/299 - study., 1951-1965. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Physical Education 326-7A - exams., 1950-1951. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Physical Education 326-7A - junior core records., 1950-1951. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Physical Education 326-7A - Methods Test - individual scores., 1951. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Physical Education 326-7A - class recorder's notes., 1951. (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Physical Education 326-7A - softball unit - lesson plans., 1951. (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Physical Education 326-7A - softball unit - lesson plans., 1951. (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Physical Education 326-7A - junior core staff meetings - recorder's reports., 1951-1952. (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Physical Education 326-7A - class notes., 1952. (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Physical Education 326-7A - group report., 1952. (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Physical Education 326-7A - individual needs from students., 1952. (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Physical Education 326-7A - exams and grades of individual students., 1952-1953. (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Physical Education 326-7A - course evaluations., 1953. (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Physical Education 326-7A - objectives, class notes., 1953. (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Physical Education 326-7A - volleyball resource unit - individual exams., 1953. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Physical Education 326-7A - individual appraisals of learning (sl)., 1953-1954. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Physical Education 326-7A - junior class roster., 1953-1954. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Physical Education 326-7A - final exam., 1954. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Physical Education 326-7A - skill testing., 1953-1954. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Physical Education 326-7A - objectives., 1954. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Physical Education 326-7B - dance unit., 1951. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Physical Education 326-7B - skills units - information sheets., 1952. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Physical Education 326-7B - spring semester report., 1952. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Physical Education 326-7B - self grading by students., 1952. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Physical Education 326-7B - final junior report - materials., 1952-1953. (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Physical Education 326-7B - philosophy unit., 1953. (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Physical Education 326-7B - spring semester report., 1953. (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Physical Education 326-7B - basketball unit - lesson plans and evaluation., 1954. (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Physical Education 326-7B - hockey teaching unit - objectives., 1954. (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Physical Education 326-7B - general materials., 1955. (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Physical Education 326-7B - aquatics unit - materials., 1955. (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Physical Education 326-7B - drill team unit - materials., 1955. (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Physical Education 326-7B - tennis unit - materials., 1955. (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Physical Education 326-7B - calendar. (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Physical Education 326-7B - staff objectives., nd. (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Physical Education 370 - girls' basketball unit., nd. (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Physical efficiency tests., nd. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Pentathalon Physical Fitness scales., nd. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Policy on basic teaching load., 1953. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Proficiency test battery. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Scoring tables for the general athletic test., nd. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Ski Slide Teaching Facility - relocation., 1959. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- State physical education - general Information., 1919-1927. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Swimming - player eligibility results., 1923-1924. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Swimming - regulations., 1960-1964. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Student teaching coordination., 1949-1953. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Syllabus of physical fitness activities., 1942. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Teacher selection and counseling. (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Teaching load - Staff Records., 1953. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Teaching load study - survey., 1952. (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Teaching requirements for physical education., 1920-1925. (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Zoology - interdepartmental curriculum., 1959-1963. (Box 7, Folder 16)